<resources>
    <string name="app_name">FinanceApp</string>

    <string name="History1">\nHISTORY OF INVESTING\n\n

According to historical accounts, investing can be traced back to the Code of Hammurabi, which was written around 1700 BCE in Mesopotamia (modern day Iraq). Historians argue that the historic code provided the framework for many of civilization’s essential laws, including the legal framework for investment. The law established a way to pledge collateral in exchange for investing in a project. In the code, the land was pledged as collateral, and anyone who broke their obligation was punished.
While the Code of Hammurabi provided the foundational laws, most modern investing goes back to 17th century Europe.

\n\nAMSTERDAMN STOCK EXCHANGE\n\n
The Amsterdam Stock Exchange is regarded as the predecessor of modern investing. It is said to operate much like current stock exchanges, which connects potential investors with investment opportunities while also allowing people in business to communicate with willing investors. Furthermore, the structure of the Amsterdam Stock Exchange itself made investing more straightforward and standardized, paving the way for the modern stock exchange.
\n</string>

    <string name="History2">
\nTHE ADVENT OF STOCK INDEXES\n\n

In the 1800s, measuring the performance of various stocks was a lot more complicated than merely checking stock indexes. Finance journalist Charles H. Dow created the first version of a stock index by averaging the top 12 stocks of crucial industrial sectors—mining companies, railroads, and steel mills, to name a few. This was called the Railroad Average, which was later renamed Dow Jones Transportation Average, and eventually, Dow Jones Industrial Average. Today, the Dow is still an essential part of the investing ecosystem, measuring 30 companies from various industries, including Coca-Cola.

Just like the industrial revolution, the emergence of the internet and other electronic communication platforms had a profound impact on the development of investing. The existence of modern communications led to the development of the NASDAQ 100, which was designed to be a market-weighted index—much like S and P—but it included more technology companies.

However, in the late 1990s, the overexposure of the NASDAQ led to investors boosting the tech bubble, which precipitated the bursting of the dotcom bubble.

        \n\nMODERN INVESTING\n\n
Today, investing is made more accessible and more straightforward for everyone around the world. Countries have their stock markets, and international brokers make it easier to invest across the globe. Modern investors can now choose from a wide range of investment products, including stocks, bonds, ETFs, mutual funds, commodities, futures, foreign currencies, and real estate, among others. Furthermore, the existence of online brokers made investing more accessible through cheaper commissions and trading fees.

New technologies and developments will, no doubt, impact modern investing as we know it. The chapters of the history of investing continues to be written.

    \n\nsource: https://www.stockpile.com/theticker/the-fascinating-history-of-investing\n\n\n\n</string>



    <string name="Basics1">\nDon’t Be Intimidated By Jargon\n\n

Don’t worry if you can’t understand the experts in the financial media right away. Much of what they say is jargon that is actually less complicated than it sounds. Don’t hesitate to ask questions; when it comes to your money, the only dumb question is the one you don’t ask. Don’t wait to invest until you feel you know everything.


\n\nUnderstand Stocks and Bonds\n\n

Almost every portfolio contains one or both of these kinds of assets.

If you buy stock in a company, you are literally buying a share of the company’s earnings. You become an owner, or shareholder, of the company. As such, you take a stake in the company’s future; you are said to have equity in the company. If the company prospers, there’s no limit to how much your share can increase in value. If the company fails, you can lose every dollar of your investment.

If you buy bonds, you’re lending money to the company (or governmental body) that issued the bonds. You become a creditor, not an owner, of the bond issuer. The bond is in effect the issuer’s IOU. You can lose the amount of the loan (your investment) if the company or governmental body fails, but the risk of loss to creditors (bondholders) is generally less than the risk for owners (shareholders). This is because, to stay in business and continue to finance its growth, a company must maintain as good a credit rating as possible, so creditors will usually pay on time if there is any way at all to do so. In addition, the law favors a company’s bondholders over its shareholders if it goes bankrupt.

Stocks are often referred to as equity investments, while bonds are considered debt instruments or income investments. A mutual fund may invest in stocks, bonds, or a combination.

Note:Before investing in a mutual fund, carefully consider its investment objectives, risks, fees, and expenses, which can be found in the prospectus available from the fund. Read it carefully before investing.
 \n</string>
    <string name="Basics2">\nDon’t Put All Your Eggs In One Basket\n\n

This is one of the most important of all investment principles, as well as the most familiar and sensible.

Consider including several different types of investments in your portfolio. Examples of investment types (sometimes called asset classes) include stocks, bonds, commodities, art, and precious metals. Cash also is considered an asset class, and includes not only currency but cash alternatives such as money market instruments, (for example, very short-term loans). Individual asset classes are often further broken down according to more precise investment characteristics (e.g., stocks of small companies, stocks of large companies, bonds issued by cities, or bonds issued by the U.S. Treasury).

Investment classes often rise and fall at different rates and times. Ideally, in a diversified portfolio of investments, if some are losing value during a particular period, others will be gaining value at the same time. The gainers may help offset the losers, which can help minimize the impact of loss from a single type of investment. The goal is to find the right balance of different assets for your portfolio given your investing goals, risk tolerance and time horizon. This process is called asset allocation.

Within each class you choose, consider diversifying further among several individual investment options within that class. For example, if you’ve decided to invest in the drug industry but are concerned about putting your entire investment into a single company, you could make smaller investments in Company A, Company B, and Company C, rather than put all your chips on one of them. Diversification alone can’t guarantee a profit or ensure against the possibility of loss, but it can help you manage the types and level of risk you take.



\n\nRecognize The Tradeoff Between An Investment’s Risk and Return\n\n

For present purposes, we define risk as the possibility that you might lose money, or that your investments will produce lower returns than expected. Return, of course, is your reward for making the investment. Return can be measured by an increase in the value of your initial investment principal, by cash payments directly to you during the life of the investment, or by a combination of the two.

There is a direct relationship between investment risk and return; the lowest-risk investments typically offer the lowest return at any given time (e.g., a federally guaranteed bank certificate of deposit). The highest-risk investments will generally offer the chance for the highest returns (e.g., stock in an Internet start-up company that may go from $12 per share to $150, then down to $3). A higher return is your potential reward for taking greater risk.

Between the extremes, every investor searches to find a level of risk–and corresponding expected return–that he or she feels comfortable with. When someone proposes an investment with a high return and suggests that it’s risk-free, remember the old adage that “If something sounds too good to be true, it probably is.”
    \n</string>
<string name="Basics3">\nUnderstand The Difference Between Investing For Growth and Investing For Income\n\n

As an investor, you face an immediate choice: Do you want growth in the value of your original investment over time, or is your goal to produce predictable, spendable current income–or a little of both?

Consistent with this investor choice, investments are frequently classified or marketed as either growth or income oriented. U.S. Treasury bills, for example, provide regular interest payments, but the value of your original investment will typically be more stable than an investment in, for example, a new software company, which will typically produce no immediate income. New companies generally reinvest any income in the business to make it grow. However, if a company is successful, the value of your stake in the company should likewise grow over time; this is known as capital appreciation.

There is no right or wrong answer to the “growth or income” question. Your decision should depend on your individual circumstances and needs (for example, your need, if any, for income today, or your need to accumulate a college fund you don’t plan to tap for 15 years). Also, each type may have its own role to play in your portfolio, for different reasons.

\n\nUnderstand The Power Of Compounding On Your Investment Returns\n\n

Compounding occurs when you “let your money ride.” When you reinvest your investment returns, you begin to earn a “return on the returns.”

A simple example of compounding occurs with a bank certificate of deposit that is allowed to roll over and be reinvested each time it matures. Interest earned in one period becomes part of the investment itself during the next period, and earns interest in subsequent periods. In the early years of an investment, the benefit of compounding on overall return is not exciting. As the years go by, however, a “rolling snowball” effect kicks in, and compounding’s long-term boost to the value of your investment becomes dramatic.

\n\nSource: Broadridge Investor Communication Solutions, Inc.\n\n\n\n</string>


    <string name="Types1"> \nCash\n\n

A cash bank deposit is the simplest, most easily understandable investment asset—and the safest. It not only gives investors precise knowledge of the interest that they’ll earn but also guarantees that they’ll get their capital back.

On the downside, the interest earned from cash socked away in a savings account seldom beats inflation. Certificates of deposit (CDs) are less liquid instruments, but they typically provide higher interest rates than those in savings accounts. However, the money put into a CD is locked up for a period of time (months to years), and there are potentially early withdrawal penalties involved.
\n\nBonds\n\n

A bond is a debt instrument representing a loan made by an investor to a borrower. A typical bond will involve either a corporation or a government agency, where the borrower will issue a fixed interest rate to the lender in exchange for using their capital. Bonds are commonplace in organizations that use them to finance operations, purchases, or other projects.

Bond rates are essentially determined by interest rates. Due to this, they are heavily traded during periods of quantitative easing or when the Federal Reserve—or other central banks—raise interest rates.3
 \n</string>
    <string name="Types2">\n\nMutual Funds\n\n

A mutual fund is a type of investment where more than one investor pools their money together to purchase securities. Mutual funds are not necessarily passive, as they are managed by portfolio managers who allocate and distribute the pooled investment into stocks, bonds, and other securities.4 Most mutual funds have a minimum investment of between $500 and $5,000, and many do not have any minimum at all. Even a relatively small investment provides exposure to as many as 100 different stocks contained within a given fund\'s portfolio.

Mutual funds are sometimes designed to mimic underlying indexes such as the S and P 500 or the Dow Jones Industrial Average. There are also many mutual funds that are actively managed, meaning that they are updated by portfolio managers who carefully track and adjust their allocations within the fund. However, these funds generally have greater costs—such as yearly management fees and front-end charges—that can cut into an investor’s returns.

Mutual funds are valued at the end of the trading day, and all buy and sell transactions are likewise executed after the market closes.

Many investment specialists advise their clients to diversity into a wide range of securities rather than focusing on just a few stocks.

\n\nExchange-Traded Funds (ETFs)\n\n

Exchange-traded funds (ETFs) have become quite popular since their introduction back in the mid-1990s. ETFs are similar to mutual funds, but they trade throughout the day, on a stock exchange. In this way, they mirror the buy-and-sell behavior of stocks. This also means that their value can change drastically during the course of a trading day.

        ETFs can track an underlying index such as the S and P 500 or any other basket of stocks with which the ETF issuer wants to underline a specific ETF. This can include anything from emerging markets to commodities, individual business sectors such as biotechnology or agriculture, and more. Due to the ease of trading and broad coverage, ETFs are extremely popular with investors.\n\n</string>
<string name="Types3">\n\nStocks\n\n

Shares of stock let investors participate in a company’s success via increases in the stock’s price and through dividends. Shareholders have a claim on the company’s assets in the event of liquidation (that is, the company going bankrupt) but do not own the assets.

Holders of common stock enjoy voting rights at shareholders’ meetings. Holders of preferred stock don’t have voting rights but do receive preference over common shareholders in terms of the dividend payments.\n\n
    Source: Investopedia.com\n\n\n\n </string>


    <string name="More1">
\nWhat Does it Mean When a Trader Buys on Margin?\n\n

Sometimes an investor needs to buy an asset by borrowing some balance from the broker. When an investor buys on margin it means that funds were transferred to the broker as payment for an asset. Then the trader uses these marginal securities in their account with the broker as securities.

It is very similar to a loan from a bank. You are able to buy more stock than you would otherwise. In order to trade on margin, you need permission from your broker and your broker needs your consent.
\n\nLeverage. What is it?\n\n

Both leverage and margin trading constitute borrowing money from a broker. However, they are quite different. While margin trading is borrowing money to further invest in assets, leverage is when you take on debt.

Leveraging is when you borrow capital when opening a position. It might be that traders want more exposure with minimal equity.
\n\nHow Does it Work?\n\n

Leverage is applied differently to margin trading. The broker applies leverage in multiples, that is multiplying the capital that is invested by trader. For example, Sage FX offers 1:500 leverage, multiplying the capital by 500 times. You can choose any amount of leverage, choosing to multiply twice, ten times or three hundred times depending on your requirement. You can apply this to both buying or selling positions.
What Should you Keep in Mind when Trading on Leverage?

It is important to always keep in mind that when using leverage,  profits may be multiplied but losses can be multiplied as well. So it is important to keep in mind certain factors when trading using leverage.

        We will go into this in our next section.\n\n</string>
    <string name="More2">\n\nWhen Should You Choose Margin and Leverage Trading?\n\n

Margin trading and leverage sound pretty convenient no? They can give you a much-needed leg up in certain situations. This is definitely appealing when opportunities present themselves to you while trading on the live market and you are not willing to miss out!

So, should you choose margin and leverage trading? As any well-seasoned trader knows, risk is a constant presence on the market (and admit it, it is part of the thrill and pleasure that trading can offer you). However, is trading on margin and choosing leverage worth the risk?

It does depend on your particular situation and circumstances. We have prepared for you the below five questions you need to ask yourself when considering margin or leverage trading. They will help you better mitigate the risks that you can encounter while opting for these tools.
\n\n1. Do You Predict Significant Profits?

The potential profits that you predict must be bigger than the accumulated interest that you will pay the broker. The rates may be quite attractive but don’t forget that you can lose a chunk of your total profit towards margin.
\n\n2. Can You Afford to Lose What You Are Risking?

Imagine you lose the assets you are thinking of trading on margin. Would it cause considerable harm to your pocket? If the answer is yes, then do not go for this option. There are indeed more opportunities available to you when you trade on margin, given it can increase your returns. Make sure you think twice if the risk is considerable. In contrast, think of the bigger picture and whether risking this much will yield enough profits in the long-term
\n\n3. Do You Have Cash Available to You Immediately?

Brokers may sell your securities should there be a margin call. Make sure you have funds available to you so as to avoid this happening.\n\n</string>

    <string name="More3">
\n\n4. Do You Have a Stop-Loss on Your Account?

\n\n5. Are You Prepared for the Market’s Volatility?

The thrill of trading on a volatile market is undisputed. Not knowing where the market will take you with the endless possibilities it creates is an adrenaline-fueled activity that is unparalleled when compared to most jobs. However, make sure you are prepared for it. The more volatile the market is, the higher the risk it presents. These risks are highlighted further when you are trading on margin or with leverage.
\n\nSource: Sagefx.com
    \n\n\n\n</string>
</resources>